Narrator: A day in the life of a Private Investigator
People think a private investigator’s job is exciting, but is it really true?
See what you think.
Speaker: On a typical day, I get up early and I go to my office. I don’t need to wear a suit.
I usually wear a shirt and trousers.
I start work at about 9. I sit at my desk and work at my computer.
I answer phone calls. I speak to colleagues. Then at about 6.00, I finish work and go home.
The calls are usually from clients – new clients or current clients.
With a new client, first I usually meet them in person in our office.
Some clients are private individuals.
Perhaps they want us to find a missing person.
Other clients are companies.
Perhaps they want us to check out if an employee is really ill or not.
Then we need to investigate the problem. We usually do this online.
Clients pay for each day we work, and they don’t want to pay a lot of money, so we try to work fast.
But sometimes our work is different, and today is one of those days.
I’m not working in the office, I’m working in the street.
I’m sitting in my car with my camera.
I’m watching and waiting. I’m hoping to see a woman.
She lives in the building opposite, and my client wants me to follow her.
I’m wearing a jacket, and I’m wearing sunglasses because I don’t want the woman to see my face.
Is this more exciting than being in the office?
Sometimes.
But waiting in a car is often boring, and it’s a long day, not just 9.00 till 6.00.
Sometimes it’s difficult to stay awake!
The life of a private investigator is not like in films and on TV.
But each case is different, and solving a case is very satisfying.